It begins on the streets. It ends here.
Coach Carter is a drama, history film directed by Thomas Carter.
Based on a true story, in which Richmond High School head basketball coach Ken Carter made
headlines in 1999 for benching his undefeated team due to poor academic results.
Ken Carter, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Kenyon Stone, played by Rob Brown.
Damien Carter, played by Robert Ri'chard.
Timo Cruz, played by Rick Gonzalez.
Junior Battle, played by Nana Gbewonyo.
Worm, played by Antwon Tanner.
Coach Carter is a 2005 American biographical
sports drama film starring Samuel L.
Jackson and directed by Thomas Carter.
It is based on the true story of Richmond High School basketball coach Ken Carter, who made headlines in
1999 for suspending his undefeated high school basketball team due to poor academic results.
The screenplay was co-written by John Gatins and Mark Schwahn.
The cast features Rob Brown, Channing Tatum (in his film debut),
Debbi Morgan, Robert Ri'chard, and singer Ashanti.
The film was a coproduction between MTV Films and Tollin/Robbins Productions.
It was commercially distributed by Paramount Pictures for
theatrical release and home video rental.
The film explores professional ethics, academics, and athletics.
The sports action in the film was coordinated by Mark Ellis.
On January 11, the film's soundtrack was released by Capitol Records, and the
film's score was composed and orchestrated by musician Trevor Rabin.
Coach Carter was released in the United States on January 14, 2005,
and earned $76.7 million on a $30 million budget.
It received a varied reception from critics.
The film explores themes of high school, scholarship, sports,
violence in schools, authoritarian education.
The tone is emotional.